ALESSIA SCACCIA

WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPER

Interpreter and translator

(+32) 0489765335

aless.scaccia@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/alessia-scaccia/



http://www.if3projets.net/wad20/alessia/

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Junior Web Application Developer (Full-Stack) with an extensive background as Language Service Provider and Customer Assistant and a Master's Degree in Conference Interpreting.

Studying, working and living in 4 European countries helped me develop a truly global mindset, the ability to adapt and the courage to take up new challenges.

After more than 7 years of professional experience as a translator, conference interpreter and language specialist, I have decided to dive in the world of programming, with a full-time Web application development training. I am currently looking for an internship opportunity in June-July 2021 to continue improving my skills.

EXPERIENCE

2013 - 2019 7 vears

Freelance Translator and Interpreter

ITALY, BELGIUM

2019 - 2020 6 months 2017 (4 months internship)

Translation Project Manager

CAPSTAN - BRUSSELS, BELGIUM

2018 - 2019 20 months

Provider Relations Manager

CIGNA - ANTWERP, BELGIUM

2017 3 months

Multilingual Client Advisor

LVMH - BRUSSELS, BELGIUM

2013 - 2014 18 months

Medical Assistant EUGIN - BARCELONA, SPAIN

EDUCATION

2020-2021 13 months

Web Application Development

INTERFACE3 - BRUSSELS, BELGIUM CECAF + Europass + C# certification (expected)

2014-2017 2 years

MA's in Conference Interpreting

UNIVERSITY OF TRIESTE, ITALY English, French, Dutch into Italian

2016 4 months

Croatian as foreign language

UNIVERSITY OF ZAGREB - CROATIA

B2+ Level Certification

2012-2013 5 months

Erasmus Program

UNIVERSITY OF MONS, BELGIUM

2009-2013 3 years

BA's in Multilingual Communication and Translation

UNIVERSITY OF TRIESTE, ITALY Major: French, Croatian, Dutch

IT SKILLS

WEB

HTML5, CSS3, XML/XSLT, AJAX, jQuery, Responsive Web Design,

Bootstrap

LANGUAGES

C#, PHP 5, SQL, Javascript, Python

FRAMEWORKS

ASP.NET, Symfony, React, Angular, Node JS

DATABASES

MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server,

phpMyAdmin

ANALYSIS

Use cases, DB analysis, UML

TOOLS

Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, XAMPP, Unit Testing, GIT

CMS

Wordpress, Drupal

PROJECT MGT

Mockup, ergonomics, hosting, SEO

referencing, RAD & SCRUM

SERVERS

Apache, IIS

LANGUAGE SKILLS

ITALIAN

FRENCH

DUTCH

ENGLISH

SPANISH

CROATIAN

I'M GOOD AT

ACTIVE LISTENING

COMMUNICATING WITH EMPATHY **BRINGING ENERGY TO THE TEAM**

ORGANIZING WORKELOWS

I REALLY ENJOY

LIVE MUSIC AND FESTIVALS STAND-UP COMEDY POLE DANCING

PODCASTS ABOUT HISTORY

Available for work as from June 2021

Driving licence: B Hiring subsidy: FPI